earlmiller.com 2008-12-16

# 

**EARL MILLER PHOTOGRAPHY, INC.  
PRIVACY STATEMENT **

This privacy statement discloses the privacy practices for all websites operated by Earl Miller Photography, Inc.

Earl Miller Photography, Inc. ("EMPI") is committed to preserving the privacy of data entrusted to us. We have developed this Privacy Policy to inform you of our information gathering and usage practices employed on any and/or all of the websites we operate.

If you feel that this company is not abiding by its posted privacy policy, you should contact:

Privacy Administrator  
Earl Miller Photography, Inc.  
9800D Topanga Canyon Blvd. #115  
Chatsworth, CA 913112   

**Information Collection and Use **  
EMPI is the sole owner of the information collected on this site.  We will not sell, share, or rent this information to others in ways different from what is disclosed in this statement.  EMPI collects information from our users at several different points on our website.  

**Registration**  
In order to use the member section of this website, a user must first complete the registration/join form.  During registration a user is required to give their contact information (such as name and email address).  This information is used to contact the user about the services on our site for which they have expressed interest.  Occassionally, we may ask for additional information beyond what is required for billing and for us to contact you. It is optional for the user to provide demographic information (such as income level and gender), and Internet usage information (such as how often you access the Internet), but encouraged so we can provide a more personalized experience on our site. 

**Order**  
We may request information from users on an order form when users order something that must be shipped.  Here a user must provide contact information (like name and shipping address) and financial information (like credit card number, expiration date).  This information is used for billing purposes and to fill customer orders.  If we have trouble processing an order, this contact information is used to get in touch with the user.

**Cookies**  
We may use cookies on our sites to speed your access to our site. A cookie is a piece of data stored on the users hard drive containing information about the user.  Usage of a cookie is in no way linked to any personally identifiable information while on our site.  Once the user closes their browser, the cookie simply terminates.  For instance, by setting a cookie on our site, the user would not have to log in a password more than once, thereby saving time while on our site.  If a user rejects the cookie, they may still use our site.  The only drawback to this is that the user will be limited in some areas of our site.  For example, the user will not be able to participate in any of our Sweepstakes, Contests or monthly Drawings that take place. Cookies can also enable us to track and target the interests of our users to enhance the experience on our site.

It is possible that some of our business partners use cookies on our site (for example, advertisers).  However, we have no access to or control over these cookies.

**Log Files**  
We use IP addresses to analyze trends, administer the site, track user’s movement, and gather broad demographic information for aggregate use.  IP addresses are generally not linked to personally identifiable information except in forums, message boards and possibly chat rooms to minimize fraudulent postings (a user impersonating another user, for example).

**Sharing  
**We will share aggregated demographic information with our partners and advertisers. This is not linked to any personal information that can identify any individual person.

We use an outside shipping company to ship merchandise orders, and a credit card processing company to bill users for goods and services. 

**Links  
**This web site contains links to other sites. Please be aware that we [SMG] are not responsible for the privacy practices of such other sites.  We encourage our users to be aware when they leave our site and to read the privacy statements of each and every web site that collects personally identifiable information.  This privacy statement applies solely to information collected by this Web site.

**Newsletter  
**If a user wishes to subscribe to our newsletter, we may ask for contact information such as name in addition to email address. Our newsletters and other email list are double opt-in and double opt-out. This means that the subscribe must reply to an email our system sends in order to successfully be added or removed to our list. We don't promote or tolerate spamming.

**Surveys & Contests  
**From time-to-time our site requests information from users via surveys or contests.  Participation in these surveys or contests is completely voluntary and the user therefore has a choice whether or not to disclose this information.  Information requested may include contact information (such as name and shipping address), and demographic information (such as zip code, age level).  Contact information will be used to notify the winners and award prizes.  Survey information will be used for purposes of monitoring or improving the use and satisfaction of this site.

**Affiliates  
**Many of our sites participate in our Earl Miller Cash affiliate program where other webmasters can refer business to us in exchange for sharing revenue generated by that referral. We have strict Terms and Conditions regulating how our affiliates may promote our sites. If you believe one of our affiliates is acting outside of acceptance practices to promote one of our sites, please contact us at the address above or by email at [support@earlmillercash.com](mailto:%20support@earlmillercash.com).

**Security  
**This website takes every precaution to protect our users’ information.  When your submit sensitive information via the website, your information is protected both online and off-line. 

When our registration/order form asks users to enter sensitive information (such as credit card number and/or social security number), that information is encrypted and is protected with the best encryption software in the industry - SSL.  While on a secure page, such as our order form, the lock icon on the bottom of Web browsers such as Netscape Navigator and Microsoft Internet Explorer becomes locked, as opposed to un-locked, or open, when you are just ‘surfing’. 

While we use SSL encryption to protect sensitive information online, we also do everything in our power to protect user-information off-line.  All of our users’ information, not just the sensitive information mentioned above, is restricted in our offices.  Only employees who need the information to perform a specific job (for example, our billing clerk or a customer service representative) are granted access to personally identifiable information.  Furthermore, ALL employees are kept up-to-date on our security and privacy practices.  Every quarter, as well as any time new policies are added, our employees are notified and/or reminded about the importance we place on privacy, and what they can do to ensure our customers’ information is protected.  Finally, the servers that we store personally identifiable information on are kept in a secure environment, behind a locked cage in a camera-monitored facility. 

If you have any questions about the security at our website, you can send an email to [security@earlmiller.com.](mailto:%20security@earlmiller.com)

**Special Offers  
**We send all new members a welcoming email to verify password and username. Established members will occasionally receive information on products, services, special deals, and a newsletter.

**Site and Service Updates** **  
** We also send the user site and service announcement updates. Members are not able to un-subscribe from service announcements, which contain important information about the service. We communicate with the user to provide requested services and in regards to issues relating to their account via email or phone.

**Correction/Updating Personal Information:  
**If a user’s personally identifiable information changes (such as your zip code), or if a user no longer desires our service, we will endeavor to provide a way to correct, update or remove that user’s personal data provided to us.  This can usually be done at the member information page **** or by emailing our Customer Support **.**   [Some sites may also provide telephone or postal mail options for updating **** or correcting **** personal information].

**Choice/Opt-out   
**Our users are given the opportunity to ‘opt-out’ of having their information used for purposes not directly related to our site at the point where we ask for the information.  For example, our order form has an ‘opt-out’ mechanism so users who buy a product from us, but don’t want any marketing material, can keep their email address off of our lists. 

Users who no longer wish to receive our newsletter or promotional materials from our partners may opt-out of receiving these communications by clicking an unsubscribe in any of our emails or by emailing us at [support@earlmiller.com](mailto:support@earlmiller.com) 

Users of our site are always notified when their information is being collected by any outside parties.  We do this so our users can make an informed choice as to whether they should proceed with services that require an outside party, or not.

**Notification of Changes  
**If we decide to change our privacy policy, we will post those changes on our privacy page on all of our sites so our users are always aware of what information we collect, how we use it, and under circumstances, if any, we disclose it.  If at any point we decide to use personally identifiable information in a manner different from that stated at the time it was collected, we will notify users by way of an email.  Users will have a choice as to whether or not we use their information in this different manner. We will use information in accordance with the privacy policy under which the information was collected.
